# William Hardesty

October 25, 2022

Columbia, MD, USA

Webpage: https://hardes11.github.io/

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/william-hardesty-414007236

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=y6uNULUAAAAJ&hl=en

### **Education**

University of Georgia

Athens, Georgia 2011- 2016

Ph.D. Mathematics

- Advisor: Daniel Nakano

- Thesis: On support varieties for algebraic groups

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

B.S. Mathematics and Computer Science

- GPA: 4.0 (summa cum laude)

Baltimore, Maryland 2007 - 2011

### **Employment**

Westlake University

Assistant Professor

University of Sydney

Research Fellow, Level B

Louisiana State University

Postdoctoral Researcher

Hangzhou, Zhejiang

2021-2022

Sydney, New South Wales

2019-2021

Baton Rouge, Louisiana

2016-2019

## **Research Summary**

My research has centered around the representation theory of **reductive algebraic groups** over fields of positive characteristic and associated objects such as **quantum groups**, **Frobenius kernels** and **restricted Lie algebras**. As well as related topics in geometry, such as the study of **perverse sheaves**, **parity sheaves**, **exotic t-structures**, the **nilpotent cone** and the **Springer resolution**. An important instance of the deep connection between representation theory and geometry arising in my work can be seen in a series of papers (joint with Pramod Achar) where we resolved the classical **Humphreys conjecture** on support varieties of tilting modules, by developing a theory of **exotic co-t-structures** for the nilpotent cone.

#### **Technical Skills**

• Programming Experience: Python, Java, C++, MATLAB

• Markup Languages: LATEX, Beamer, XML, HTML

• Software: NumPy, SymPy, Maple, Mathematica, FEniCS

#### **Publications**

- 13. (with P. Achar) Silting complexes of coherent sheaves and the Humphreys conjecture, submitted, arXiv:1810.06157.
- 12. (with P. Achar) Nilpotent centralizers and good filtrations, to appear in **Transformation Groups**.
- 11. (with P. Achar) Co-t-structures on derived categories of coherent sheaves and the cohomology of tilting modules, to appear in **Representation Theory**.
- 10. (with P. Achar, S. Riche) Integral exotic sheaves and the modular Lusztig-Vogan bijection, to appear in **Journal of the London Mathematical Society**.
- 9. On the centralizer of a balanced nilpotent section, submitted, arXiv:1810.06157.
- 8. Explicit calculations in an infinitesimal singular block of  $SL_N$ , **Proceedings of the Edinburgh** Mathematical Society 65 (1), 19 52.
- 7. (with P. Achar, S. Riche) Conjectures on tilting modules and antispherical *p*-cells, to appear in **RIMS Kokyuroku Bessatsu**, arXiv:1812.09960.
- 6. (with P. Achar, S. Riche) Representation theory of disconnected reductive groups, **Documenta** Mathematica 25 (2020), 2149-2177.
- 5. (with P. Achar) Calculations with graded perverse coherent sheaves, **The Quarterly Journal of Mathematics** 70 (4), 1327-1352.
- 4. (with P. Achar, S. Riche) On the Humphreys conjecture on support varieties, **Transformation** Groups 24 (3), 597-657.
- 3. On support varieties and the Humphreys conjecture in type A, Adv. Math. 329 (2018), 392–421.
- (with D. Nakano, P. Sobaje) On the existence of Mock Injective modules for algebraic groups, Bull. Lond. Math. Soc. 49 (2017).
- 1. Support varieties of line bundle cohomology groups for  $SL_3(k)$ , **J. Algebra** 448 (2016), 127-173.

#### Teaching Experience

- Louisiana State University: Honors Calculus I, Calculus II, Ordinary Differential Equations, Discrete Mathematics
- University of Georgia: Precalculus, Calculus I

#### Awards. Grants & Honours

Graduate Student Travel Grant to the Joint Mathematics Meetings	2016
University of Georgia, Graduate Student Assistantship	2013
Outstanding Senior in Mathematics, University of Maryland, Baltimore County	2010
Outstanding Graduating Senior in Mathematics, University of Maryland, Baltimore County	2009

#### **Service**

- Co-organizer for the Southeastern Lie Theory Worskhop XI (Baton Rouge, May 2019)
- Service as a T.A. for Oberwolfach Seminar: Character Formulas for Reductive Algebraic Groups Oberwolfach, Germany (November 2018)
- Service as an anonymous referee for *International Mathematics Research Notices*, *Journal of Combinatorial Theory, Series A*, and multiple conference proceedings journals.